Ksenia Ilinykh



ksenia.ilinyh@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/kseniailinykh



https://kseniailinyh.github.io/

Summary

Hi, I'm Ksenia, a product designer with over 9 years of SaaS experience.

I have a lot of experience in designing B2B products: internal billing, CRM, financial analysis system. I have worked in small and big product teams, in a start-up, and in an established product.

I love turning chaos into an easy-to-use interface that solves customer's problems.

One of my superpowers is mischief: I love using funny and entertaining tricks in my everyday work. Once, I drew a comic with tasks details for the developer who didn't like to read tasks descriptions. And one day I put Lumpy Space Princess from the TV show "Adventure Time" into my prototypes. She helped me to diversify my routine task.

Experience

Product Designer

Cube Dev

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022 (4 months)

Cube Dev is a series A start-up that provides headless business intelligence for building analytics applications. The paid product is a Cube Cloud.

I became the first product designer in the product team and built the design process from the scratch:

- I have distinguished the design into a separate stage in the development process.
- Organized and implemented a design-to-dev handoff process.
- Together with a product manager, we prioritized the backlog, and defined the roadmap for design.

I have dealt with a difficult domain of developer's frameworks and non-trivial use cases. Was responsible for the end-to-end design.

K Head of Design Bureau

Контур

Nov 2019 - Sep 2021 (1 year 11 months)

Kontur is a B2B software company with more than 70 product teams, big and small. Not every product team in the company needs a full-time product designer, but sometimes there is a part-time job for them. For such teams, I created a new design team "Bureau", in which designers work for several products at the same time.

- I raised Bureau to 5 designers: hired, onboarded, and mentored them. I assigned tasks according to the designer's workload and communicated with product teams.
- I shaped the whole process of communication with product teams and created a guide on how to work with our team: https://kseniailinyh.github.io/portfolio/bureau-guide.html

- In 2021, 5 designers in Bureau provided end-to-end design for 30 product teams. 10 startups were launched without dedicated designers.

★ Product Designer

Контур

Dec 2012 - Sep 2021 (8 years 10 months)

- Helped to launch 3 new products designing interfaces from the scratch: a product for school teachers (web and mobile UI), a product for small and midsize businesses to help them comply with GDPR-like regulations that has acquired more than 10,000 paying enterprise customers, and an internal CRM for programer's job interview.
- Launched more than 10 user testing: prepared interactive prototypes, recruited users, made more than 15 interviews.
- Invented and organized a brand-new prototype testing process: together with my colleague, I created a website with an interactive prototype and a survey. We collected 300+ user feedback for 2 days. It was a few years before Maze appeared. I gave a speech at it: https://www.youtube.com/watch? v=t_zKEjuiins (RU)

Education



Ural State University named after A.M.Gorky

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science Sep 2005 - Jun 2009

Skills

Product Design • User Interface Design • Interaction Design • UX Research • Mobile Application Design • Figma (Software)